Paul Oluyemi

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

oluola96@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | Medium | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full Stack Software Engineer with a passion for developing innovative programs using a variety of technologies such as Ruby on Rails, Python, Django, MongoDB, Mongoose, PostgreSQL, MySQL, React, and JavaScript. Focus is on creating efficient and effective software solutions that contribute to organizational success

Expertise lies in developing reliable and user-friendly systems, as well as mentoring and managing teams of 5+ developers to build software programs and effectively track changes. Confident communicator, strategic thinker, and innovative creator who can develop customized software to meet organizational needs, highlight their core competencies, and further their success

SKILLS

Front-End: TypeScript, JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, Bootstrap, Tailwind, HTML5, CSS3

Back-End: Python, Django, Ruby & Ruby on Rails, Mongoose & MongoDB, Node.Js & Express.Js, MySQL & PostgreSQL

Testing & Debugging: React Testing Library, Redux DevTools, Python Debugger (PDB), Django Debug Toolbar, Ruby Debugger

Tools & Methods: Docker & DockerHub, Git & GitHub, Test Driven Development (TDD), Behavior Driven Development (BDD), Agile Methodology, Visual Studio Code, Figma, Canvas, Postman, Github CodeSpace, Github, GitLab, Netlify, Heroku, Chrome Dev Tools, Code analyzers, and Linters.

Professional: Communication, Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring, Time management and Project management, Problem-solving, and Critical thinking and ability to learn new things quickly.

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS Full Stack Web Developer

Remote July 2022 - Present

<u>Leaderboard</u> — This JavaScript project is a leaderboard that ranks results in real-time, displaying users' exact positions based on their scores.

- Built with: Git, Github, Webpack, React Reactjs, JavaScript, Jquery, HTML5, and CSS3.
- The platform features a simple and intuitive interface.
- Optimized for handling large volumes of data and providing a seamless user experience.
- The leaderboard displays scores in a descending order, starting from the highest and going down to the lowest.

<u>To Do List</u> — This is a to-do list application that enables users to manage their tasks effectively

- Built with: JavaScript, HTML5, and CSS3, Git & Github
- Task management: Users can create, edit, and delete tasks as needed.
- Task completion tracking: Users can mark tasks as completed once they are finished.
- **Search functionality:** The application provides search functionality to help users find specific tasks quickly and easily.
- Task categorization and prioritization: Users can categorize their tasks and assign priority levels to each task.

<u>Calculator App</u> — Make simple calculations. -Read a random math-related quote.

- Built with: Git, Github, Webpack, React Reactjs, Redux, JavaScript, Jquery, HTML5, and CSS3.
- Includes a memory feature to store and recall values.

- Allows users to input decimals and negative numbers.
- Offers a random math-related quote on each use.
- Provides a clear button to clear the current calculation.

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer) February, 2022 – Present

- Mentored junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE January, 2022 – May, 2023

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

THE FEDERAL UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY, AKURE

November, 2011 - October 2016

First degree, Marine Science and Technology

- Scientific research and methodology: Highlight your experience in conducting research, formulating hypotheses, designing experiments, and analyzing results. This demonstrates your ability to approach problems systematically and generate evidence-based conclusions.
- **Data collection and management:** You would have gained experience in collecting, organizing, and managing large datasets, which can be applied to software development projects involving data handling.